<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CoderDojo Navan</title>
    <link>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on CoderDojo Navan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 19:17:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/new.coderdojonavan.ie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>We Need Mentors</title>
      <link>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/post/we-need-mentors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 19:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/post/we-need-mentors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Appeal for NEW and/or past mentors! Do you have sme coding/IT experience? Can
you volunteer 2 hours of your choice between 11:00 and 15:00 each Saturday for
6 weeks, in whatever area of expertise you can assist with? Examples are HTML,
App Inventor and Scratch for beginners of advanced. Or a course based on your
area of expertise for our more experienced students as we welcome new options.
Contact us at coderdojonavan@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are only able to offer classes based on the kind support of volunteers, so
if you know of anyone that might be able to help, please encourage them to get
involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch</title>
      <link>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/class/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 13:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/class/scratch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;scratch&#34;&gt;Scratch&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scratch is a programming language and an online community where children can
program and share interactive media such as stories, games, and animation with
people from all over the world. As children create with Scratch, they learn to
think creatively, work collaboratively, and reason systematically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Scratch is primarily designed for 8 to 16 year olds, it is also used by
people of all ages, including younger children with their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scratch-beginners&#34;&gt;Scratch Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;couse-times&#34;&gt;Couse Times:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring 2017 session: 12:30 - 14:30&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This class is suitable for complete beginners to Scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please bring headphones and a mouse and install Scratch Offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this is your first time attending, please install Scratch on your laptop
if it is not there already - Scratch is free and can be downloaded at the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scratch.mit.edu/scratch2download/&#34;&gt;Scratch Download Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go</title>
      <link>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/class/go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 13:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/class/go/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;go&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-times&#34;&gt;Course Times:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring 2017 session: 11:00 - 13:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this course we will explore the world of Go, free, fast, easy to learn
language very similar to Python. We will be making basic chatbots - programs
which will respond to what you write in chat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This couse is suitable for kids with some level of programming experience, such
as Python, Scratch or other language. Students should be familiar with basic
computer functions, such as downloading and opening files. There will be typing
involved. Before first class please have the following software installed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/dl&#34;&gt;Go 1.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/download&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Optional - &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/download&#34;&gt;NotePad++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going over &lt;a href=&#34;https://try.github.io&#34;&gt;Github&amp;rsquo;s Git Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; would help you
understand Git, which will be used to save and share your code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information</title>
      <link>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 18:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new.coderdojonavan.ie/info/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;information&#34;&gt;INFORMATION&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CoderDojo Navan&lt;/strong&gt; is a cool, free environment where kidfs can learn how to
program, build wbesites, animated characters and games with different software
programs and languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the mentors are volunteers who either teach or work in IT, and our aim is
to help you develop the skills you want to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will now be holding our Dojo sessions for  6 consecutive Sataurdays for a 2
hour session during a 4 hour window; 11:00 - 15:00 each week, instead of once
a month. The actual times have been determined by the mentor leading each
particular class. Therefore some classes will be 11:00 - 13:00, others
12:00-14:00 and some 13:00 - 15:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insert image here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the volunteer nature of the Dojo, it is requested that those signing up
for a course, do so with the intention of attending all 6 Saturdays in
recognition of the time being given by our volunteer mentors. The students
that attend all dates will then be awarded a course completion certificate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as &amp;lsquo;Scratch&amp;rsquo;, which is the coding for beginners and younger students,
we are now offering the following more advanced courses specifically targeting
older kids that have perhaps attended in the past or are self-taught and wish
to broaden their skills in any of the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website Design&lt;/strong&gt; - Do you have a hobby or want to share your interests?
Then share these and more on your very own website. Learn how to create web
pages in HTML and design each page using CSS for layouts, fonts, colours etc.
With this knowledge you can then build and share your website on the web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Interface (UI) Design&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your app, game or web page to life by
creating graphical user interfaces that engage and inspire people. Users need
to feel comfortable with the system they are using and it needs to respond
accordingly, i.e. buttons should behave like buttons and aliens should
wiggle. Using free tools like Inkscape and GIMP, learn to take your blank
canvas and put your ideas to life in a way that people enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; - Want to create a new gaming experience by exploring the magical
world of Minecraft programming? You&amp;rsquo;ve probably breaten the creepers,
travelled deep into caves and maybe even gone to The End and back - but have
you ever transformed a sword into a magic wand? Build a palace in a blink of
an eye? Designed to own colour-changing disco dance floor? Learn to do this
and and more in Minecraft with the power of Python!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dev Ops&lt;/strong&gt; - (Development/Operations) - All websites sit on servers and
DevOps are the people who put up and manage the websites online. Learn to use
tools for controlling the website code/web app using Git, deploying code to
servers, using Linux, server administration and open source and its benefits.
All to ensure that your website stays online and is easy to maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all courses except &amp;lsquo;Scratch&amp;rsquo;, students should already be familiar with
basic computer functions including downloading, opening files, saving
information to different locations and basic keyboard skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be limited space for each course. Our regulars and those on the
waiting list shall be contacted by emails over the comming days with any
available places thereafter announced here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in any taking part or if you are interested in mentoring
or offering your skills as a speaekr to a class for a once off workshop on
specialized software (such as Photoshop, AutoCAD, etc.) or hardware workshop,
please email us on coderdojonavan@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-details-on-our-sessions&#34;&gt;Some details on our sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We meet on each Saturday for six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Booking ahead is essential. Tickets are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://zen.coderdojo.com/dojo/ie/meath/unity-centre-windtown-navan-co-meath/navan&#34;&gt;CoderDojo Zen&lt;/a&gt;
page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sessions run at various times throughout the day: 11:00 to 15:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every child must have a parent or adult in charge!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parents must stay with child during the session (helping if possible).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoderDojo Navan is supported by The Unity Centre, Navan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out and Like our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/CoderDojoNavan/&#34;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-need-to-bring&#34;&gt;What do you need to bring:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please bring a Wi-Fi neabled laptop, fully charged if possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are attending a Scratch class, please install &lt;a href=&#34;https://scratch.mit.edu/scratch2download/&#34;&gt;Scratch 2.0&lt;/a&gt;
on your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It woud be a good idea to bring a USB key to save your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For sprite-drawing we recommend you bring a pair of headphones and a mouse
(even an old wired mouse) as the Paint Editor doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit a laptop mouse
 pad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are new to the CoderDojo Navan, you can pre-register as a member by
downloading our &lt;a href=&#34;new.coderdojonavan.ie/coderdojo-navan-member-registration-and-parental-permission-form.pdf&#34;&gt;registration form&lt;/a&gt;,
 fill out and present it to a mentor when you arrive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;happy-coding&#34;&gt;Happy Coding!&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>